Sara Blalock Ng

University of Washington Guggenheim Hall sbng@uw.edu

RESEARCH

I am a Ph.D. student in Computational Linguistics at the University of Washington. I do Natural Language Processing on corpus speech data. My areas of interest include use of linguistic structures in conjunction with deep learning methods, language modeling, semantic labeling, and NLP in general for low-resource languages, especially languages without orthographic forms. My research goal is to create innovative algorithmic advances and to align existing frameworks with the needs of underrepresented language communities. I believe that speech is a exciting frontier space for the implementation of the state-of-the-art in deep learning for text data.

EDUCATION

current University of Washington, Seattle, WA

2nd-year Ph.D. student in Computational Linguistics

2017 University of Utah, Salt Lake City, UT

Bachelor of Science, Applied Mathematics Honors Bachelor of Arts, Linguistics

- The sis: $\mathit{Musical\ Text-Setting\ as\ Evidence\ for\ Syllabification\ of\ Highly\ Moraic}$

Structures in English
- Advisor: Dr. Abby Kaplan

2016 University of Utah, Salt Lake City, UT

TESOL (Teaching English to Students of Other Languages) Certificate

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

2017-2018 Research Assistant under Dr. Sharon Hargus on Sahaptin, Witsuwit'en,

Deg Xinag, and Kwadacha language projects.

2016-2017 Undergraduate research group in phonology, under the direction of

Dr. Abby Kaplan, University of Utah

LANGUAGES

Python (incl. nltk, pytorch) French (working)
Javascript Spanish (basic)
R Hoisanva (heritage)
Matlab

HTML, CSS Java (basic)

CONFERENCES AND PRESENTATIONS

2018	Musical Evidence for Syllabification Patterns of Highly Moraic Structures in English Linguistic Society of America, with Abby Kaplan and Joselyn Rodriguez, poster session
2017	Musical Evidence for Syllabification Patterns in English
	University of Utah Student Conference in Linguistics, with Jenica Jessen &
	Joselyn Rodriguez, presentation
2017	Musical Evidence for Syllabification Patterns of Highly Moraic Structures in English
	Undergraduate Research Symposium, University of Utah, with Jenica Jessen, poster session
2014	Englishes in the African Diaspora
2014	University of Utah Social Justice Scholars, panel presentation
	, <u> </u>

TEACHING

2018	Teaching Assistant LING 570: Shallow Processing Techniques for Natural Language Processing
2018	Teaching Assistant LING 269: Swearing and Taboo Language University of Washington
2016	Student Teacher Intermediate ESL and Content ESL Cottonwood High School (UT)
2015	Student Teacher ESL Reading and Lanugage Murray High School (UT)

AWARDS AND SCHOLARSHIPS

2018	Travel Scholarship for Ethics in NLP workshop at NAACL-HLT 2018
2017	Top Scholar Award, University of Washington Graduate School
2017	Small Grant (\$200), Undergraduate Research Opportunities Program,
	University of Utah
2013	President's Scholarship (full-tuition Scholarship), University of Utah
2013	National Merit Scholarship, National Merit Scholarship Program

WORK EXPERIENCE

2014, 2016-2017 Communications Assistant, CaptionCall 2014-2017 Mathematics Tutor